time and he he you know he said it too
man this this guy's a stealer so with
that excited um you know gives us a lot
of options on the offensive line and um
yeah like I said I can't wait coach
>> yes I'm very excited about Max um our
offensive line coaches are bouncing off
the wall I know it's a little late you
guys are look look like you're dragging
a little bit sorry to hold you in there
u but uh I can't tell you enough about
you don't have enough big men up front
he is a great fit for us just a stud of
a young man um you know throughout the
process you know you heard about him um
a little bit early and he just kept
growing and growing and growing through
the evaluation so and as we really
winded it down this week um he you know
just frankly just kept climbing up our
board so we were just real excited that
he was there and I think it's an
excellent pick pick for us and uh he'll
be a great addition to our offensive
line
>> question about is the pick any
reflection on Broadick Johnson
>> I mean sure that's a little bit of a
concern you guys have heard me talk
about that, but um you know we have guys
that have you know you you guys always
hear me talk about versatility too,
Jerry and and we got guys on the
offensive line that can play different
positions in the offensive line and uh
as I mentioned we have options. Um
>> does it raise the possibility of moving?
I know it's a little early but when we
spot a thought on the left
>> well I I think all those things are you
know u discussions that will occur after
the draft. you know, we we had two
really good days Monday and Tuesday that
that to work with our men. Um, and and
frankly, we we looked at as much
position flex throughout the individual
drills that that we did uh work with the
the offensive line. We even had some,
you know, not team drills, but group
activity that we worked a number of the
offensive linemen both left and right.
So, I mean, that's it's part of being a
new staff. Uh, they're excited about it.
We wanted to see what what this weekend
brings and we're off to a hell of a
start for our offensive line room. So,
position flex is huge. It's bigger than
ever in the NFL. 17 games is real and
have and add Max to this group is uh I
can't tell you how excited we are with
the pick.
>> Guard is an option maybe.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Would would that include guard as an
option possibly with Max?
>> With Max? No. We I mean we'll start him
off at tackle. I mean, you know, once
again, I want to we want to work with
them and um you know, I know our line
coaches had a zoom with them the other
day and and um man, I mean, just it's
nice to see it come together and in this
this evaluation starting with Omar and
the personnel staff um and he's uh made
a huge impression on us. I think he's a
great fit for us.
>> So, he's right tackle right tackle only.
Is that where he's going to start?
>> Yes, I mean
I just talked about position flex. I
mean, he's part of the conversation.
>> Could Troy Falanu move the guard too in
that conversation? Michael or Omar?
>> Lots of options there. We got options.
>> Yeah.
>> Omar, how much do you feel he's tapped
into his potential at this point?
>> Oh, he's just he's just getting started.
You know, he hasn't played a lot of
football in his life and it's he's only
going to get better.
>> This is a challenging position. What
have you learned about what it takes to
develop a tackle so that he's ready
sooner than later uh to step in and
start?
I mean, that's that's a pretty general
question, but I think it's specifically
to tonight. I mean, that's why it's
important u to to to get Max here, see
where he fits. Um, you know, it's it's
it's not as much as just, you know, what
he's done at Arizona State. It's really
the techniques and how we're going to
play and and things like that. So, uh,
when you get everybody here, which, you
know, we will do in two weeks, then
we'll we'll have a better idea exactly
what needs what he needs to work on.
>> Moved up, uh, throughout the process,
seen the ball, combine, that kind of
stuff. Is that what what specifically
made him impression?
>> I say he he won through the, uh, through
the process. I mean, he really did, you
know, um,
he won everywhere he was. It's the
Senior Bowl, the combine, you know, the
interaction we had through our Zooms. Um
it just it just felt right.
>> Did uh was it always offensive line or
how the board broke brought you to the
offense?
>> You know, you trust your board. Um but
you know, the way it shake it shook out.
Yeah. It just, you know, it brought us
to the position and it it's the right it
was the right pick for us.
>> How much did Philadelphia trading up
jumping you guys influence or or cause
you guys to pivot with that pick? you
know, I think all all um all those
things that happen around us um you
know, affect the conversations, but just
the draft.
>> Both of you mentioned the impression he
made on you. What is it specifically
about him and your interactions with him
that made you feel he was the fit here?
>> Well, I mean, I'll just talk from the
coach's perspective. You got to
remember, you know, Omar and the
personnel staff, they've been working on
this, you know, for 12 months. Um you're
we're new staff, you get in place, so
we're later to the game. you know,
didn't know a whole lot. I didn't know a
whole lot about Max two months ago. And
so, as you know, the you know, you go
through the process with the with the
staff. I mean, he's someone that I know
just with between myself and the
offensive line coaches. We've been
talking a lot about him lately.
>> Mike, how do you see his background in
soccer and basketball before he
committed to football show up and his
footwork and his game? Oh, I just I
think the biggest thing when you watch
lineman play, you know, you know, you
want to see him strike and stick and and
with that, you know, the balance in the
footwork, you know, his ability to stay
alive on second and third reaction when
he does engage. I think it's it's all
over the video.
>> You also talking about flexibility uh
with your offensive linement. Is that
good to because the injuries in the NFL
kind of squared across the board. Was
that good that you can plug people in in
and out of your offense and keep on
going in case of injury?
>> Yeah, def. Yes, definitely. It's it's I
think it's it's value that that that you
you definitely look into especially when
you get down to the 53man roster because
you know it's one thing for your nine 10
ever how many linemen you keep each year
um to play on a 53 but how do they get
up on a 48? So uh position flex is very
very important you know the second third
center you know the fourth tackle that I
mean that's those are all important
conversations those are the
conversations you have internally and uh
so anytime I know from from my
perspective as a coach and the
evaluation process I I hold position
flex the value of it very high
>> did you all consider moving up or was it
always the plan to stay where you were
at 21? you know, we we we uh like I
mentioned the other day, we field calls,
you know, we all talk and um you know,
there were some opportunities to move
up, there's some opportunities to move
back and um it just we just, you know,
didn't want to trade away from this
player. It just felt good.
>> Was there a moment where he really got
on your radar?
>> What's that?
>> Is there a moment where he really got on
your radar? Can you remember like a
moment where he's where he really stood
out to you? Yeah, I I would say um
really when we were going through our
February draft meetings, that's really
when he he uh you know, and the scouts
came back. I wasn't at the Senior Bowl
when the scouts came back and we started
talking about the guys that were there
and um uh and then you know, we got to
our February meetings and that's that's
when he really really grabbed our
attention there and it just he just kept
getting better and better for us with
him.
>> Guys, two more. Two more.
>> One more. Since Andy came on in 22, you
guys have spent a lot of early draft
capital on offensive lineman. How
reflective is this of kind of his entire
strategy that he had at previous
destinations?
>> Uh from pre I mean you'd have to ask
Andy that question, but I mean I think
from uh day one we've said uh you know
those big guys are important to us.
>> Omar uh Bill and Noeo is similar in in
experience and size.
>> Did you see any of that?
>> You said an owl. Would you say?
>> Yeah. Illinois
similar that he was inexperienced and
tall.
>> Yeah. I mean, from the experience
standpoint, maybe a little bit, but I
mean Al was uh 6'9. I mean, he was uh so
um but yeah, there's this kid's uh
football is ahead of him. I mean, he's
only going to get better and better.
Like I said, it's it's the more he
plays, he's such a talented football
player, and you know, he hasn't played a
lot of football and I'm just excited
about the future holds for him with us.
All right. And we'll get Max on the
phone shortly. Thanks, guys.